<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: learning | Agam's Mashed-Up Pome]]></title>
  <link href="http://agam.github.io/blog/categories/learning/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://agam.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-27T08:04:29+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://agam.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Agam]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stuff I'd like to learn in 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://agam.github.io/blog/2015/01/07/stuff-id-like-to-learn-in-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-07T06:49:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://agam.github.io/blog/2015/01/07/stuff-id-like-to-learn-in-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ah yes, the time of New Year&rsquo;s Resolutions. It never ends. Many weeks pass by in a haze of &ldquo;<em>shoulds</em>&rdquo;. So here&rsquo;s something more to add on.</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Keep playing with Go. It&rsquo;s a great, simple language. In particular, I want to try out a whole bunch of crazy experiments.</p></li>
<li><p>Think about the &ldquo;simple text games&rdquo; book. Or bury the idea as soon as possible.</p></li>
</ul>


<p><del>&ndash; Learn a bit more about the JVM (perhaps through Clojure?)</del></p>

<ul>
<li>Stem the atrophy in algorithmic skills</li>
</ul>


<p>&hellip; and there&rsquo;s more I can&rsquo;t remember right now. The first two seem self-evident, so a bit more about the third and fourth. I&rsquo;ve had a deep dislike for all things <em>Microsoft and Java</em> for over ten years now, and I think it&rsquo;s all mostly FUD.</p>

<p>In the case of Microsoft, it was because everything I tried to learn became deprecated as fast as I learnt it, and I quit in disgust (I&rsquo;m told I quit before giving the CLR and C# a fair chance). I was quite naive fifteen years ago and thought that <em>everything</em> that was current <em>then</em> was going to last forever. This extended to such stuff as Frontpage, DDE, COM, RDO &hellip; you get the idea.</p>

<p>For Java it&rsquo;s more vague. I think I never got the <em>hang</em> of it, and then I had a lot of &ldquo;<em>design pattern crap</em>&rdquo; thrown in my face, and my long-last impression was one of incredible, pointless verbosity. Last year though we had someone join our team who had done <em>RealWorkInJava &trade;</em>, and after talking to him it didn&rsquo;t seem all that bad. In particular, the JVM seemed like something worth knowing.</p>

<p>I have pretty much <em>zero</em> experience with hosted languages. One of the reasons for this might be that I always want to know what&rsquo;s &ldquo;really happening underneath&rdquo;, and am deeply suspicious of situations when I <em>cannot</em> know (this is also why I prefer Ocaml/F# over Haskell, but  that&rsquo;s a whole other blog post).</p>

<p><del>Add to this the fact that I&rsquo;ve always been curious about Clojure, to discover all its differences from Common Lisp on my own (there are several rants for and against it online, but there&rsquo;s only one way to find out for sure), and it&rsquo;s a natural outlet for exploration.</del></p>

<p>Which brings me to the fourth point &hellip; I feel I&rsquo;ve seriously forgotten <em>a lot</em> of theory, both in Math and CS, and it&rsquo;s <em>frightening</em>. So I&rsquo;m hoping to weave that (<em>somehow</em>) into my Clojure exploration and kill many birds with one stone.</p>

<p>So yeah, we&rsquo;ll find out how this all worked out, same time next year :)</p>

<p><strong>Update (1/13): This is a bunch of crap</strong> I just realized I wrote a <a href="http://agam.github.io/blog/2014/01/05/resolutions/">similar post</a> last year and did <em>nothing</em> about it (well, ok, I <em>did</em> do the <em>r/dailyprogrammer</em> stuff, more or less), so scratch all of the above. I&rsquo;ll leave it up to remind myself of how foolish this is. I&rsquo;m guessing this will reoccur the same time next year :P. Perhaps the best way out is to make <em>no resolutions</em>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Gardens of Go]]></title>
    <link href="http://agam.github.io/blog/2014/12/17/the-gardens-of-go/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-17T05:54:20+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://agam.github.io/blog/2014/12/17/the-gardens-of-go</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There are many &ldquo;teaching&rdquo; languages, though a contender these days is harder to establish, given the amount of choice available. For very young kids, the Scratch<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> framework is appropriate, while for slightly older kids, Python might be a better option.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;d like to suggest another option (for slightly older kids), that might seem atypical at first: Go! Yes, I do believe the &ldquo;Gopher language&rdquo;, used in many real production servers today, can realistically do double duty as a beginner language for kids.</p>

<p>This is the point where I make an analogy, and it goes something like this: I think Go can be to kids today what BASIC<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> was to me<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" rel="footnote">3</a></sup>, i.e. as a way to experiment with and play around in a &ldquo;text-mode&rdquo; world, while getting very quick feedback, and building &ldquo;complete&rdquo; programs.</p>

<p>An objection many people have is along the lines of, &ldquo;Oh no! You don&rsquo;t get it! Kids love <em>only</em> flashy, shiny stuff! You need animation, and nothing else will do!&rdquo; Perhaps several kids do; perhaps several adults do as well. These are not my target audience; I&rsquo;ll leave it at that.</p>

<p>No, I <em>do</em> believe that many kids <em>will</em> love the parameterized<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" rel="footnote">4</a></sup> freedom offered, and learn to create and modify small Go programs. One of the <em>best</em> sources of fun for me were old BASIC games books<sup id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5" rel="footnote">5</a></sup>, from where I used to type out entire<sup id="fnref:6"><a href="#fn:6" rel="footnote">6</a></sup> programs (and then spend time fixing the inevitable typos that resulted).</p>

<p>Go has a simple syntax, that&rsquo;s easy to pick up (you can do a lot with just <code>int</code>s and <code>string</code>s!) and quick to run. All<sup id="fnref:7"><a href="#fn:7" rel="footnote">7</a></sup> that remains to be done is to come up with a series of little games<sup id="fnref:8"><a href="#fn:8" rel="footnote">8</a></sup>, of increasing complexity and lots of fun.</p>

<p><em>Statutory Warning: Heh, I&rsquo;m just writing this in a burst of optimism (this might be a useless idea).</em></p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p><a href="http://scratch.mit.edu/">http://scratch.mit.edu/</a><a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>See <a href="http://time.com/69316/basic/">this TIME magazine article</a> for a nice restrospective look<a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>I see the jokes coming: no, I don&rsquo;t mean as a way to learn the <code>GOSUB &lt;line_number&gt;</code> syntax.<a href="#fnref:3" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p>All the features of an &ldquo;opinionated&rdquo; language; <code>gofmt</code>, <code>go run</code> and all that goodness.<a href="#fnref:4" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:5">
<p>Such as <a href="http://www.amazon.com/BASIC-Computer-Games-Microcomputer-Edition/dp/0894800523">this one</a>, or <a href="http://www.amazon.com/More-Basic-Computer-Games-David/dp/0894801376/ref=pd_sim_b_1?ie=UTF8&amp;refRID=1VG0C6RVPESH91TK90QJ">this one</a><a href="#fnref:5" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:6">
<p>In practice, my younger brother dictated them to me (which must&rsquo;ve been a terrible ordeal, but I didn&rsquo;t realize it at the time!)<a href="#fnref:6" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:7">
<p>Easier said than done, I know, I know.<a href="#fnref:7" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:8">
<p>The title of this post was chosen in the style of <a href="http://www.realmofracket.com/">&ldquo;The Realm of Racket&rdquo;</a> and <a href="http://landoflisp.com/">&ldquo;The Land of Lisp&rdquo;</a><a href="#fnref:8" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
