<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: AlwaysBeCoding, | Agam's Mashed-Up Pome]]></title>
  <link href="http://agam.github.io/blog/categories/alwaysbecoding/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://agam.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-24T23:53:25+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://agam.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Agam]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Programming Fun: Nuts and Bolts]]></title>
    <link href="http://agam.github.io/blog/2014/01/19/programming-fun-nuts-and-bolts/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-19T00:39:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://agam.github.io/blog/2014/01/19/programming-fun-nuts-and-bolts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/dailyprogrammer/comments/1sob1e/121113_challenge_144_easy_nuts_bolts/">This one</a> is <em>too easy</em> but included anyway for completeness (why not?)</p>

<p>```</p>

<h2>Input Description</h2>

<p>The first line of input will be an integer N, which is for the number of rows
in each list. Each list has N-lines of two space-delimited strings: the first
string will be the unique item name (without spaces), the second string will be
the price (in whole-integer cents). The second list, following the same format,
will have the same unique item-names, but with the correct price. Note that the
lists may not be in the same order!</p>

<h2>Output Description</h2>

<p>For each item that has had its price changed, print a row with the item name
and the price difference (in cents). Print the sign of the change (e.g. &lsquo;+&rsquo; for
a growth in price, or &lsquo;&ndash;&rsquo; for a loss in price). Order does not matter for
output.</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>{% gist 8498879 %}</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Programming Fun: Telephone Keypads]]></title>
    <link href="http://agam.github.io/blog/2014/01/18/programming-fun-telephone-keypads/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-18T02:21:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://agam.github.io/blog/2014/01/18/programming-fun-telephone-keypads</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/dailyprogrammer/comments/1sody4/12113_challenge_139_intermediate_telephone_keypads/">This is a <em>medium</em> level problem</a>  with two levels of difficulty.</p>

<p>```</p>

<h2>Input Description</h2>

<p>On standard console input, you will be given an array of digits (0 to 9) and
spaces. All digits will be space-delimited, unless the digits represent
multiple presses of the same button (for example pressing 2 twice gives you the
letter &lsquo;B&rsquo;).  Use the modern Telephone Keypads digit-letter layout:
0 = Not used
1 = Not used
2 = ABC
3 = DEF
4 = GHI
5 = JKL
6 = MNO
7 = PQRS
8 = TUV
9 = WXYZ
You may use any source for looking up English-language words, though this
simple English-language dictionary is complete enough for the challenge.</p>

<h2>Output Description</h2>

<p>Print a list of all best-fitting words, meaning words that start with the word
generated using the given input on a telephone keypad. You do not have to only
print words of the same length as the input (e.g. even if the input is
4-digits, it&rsquo;s possible there are many long words that start with those
4-digits).
```</p>

<p>You could do this by reading the dictionary into a vector of strings, then figuring out the prefix determined by the input and matching it against each dictionary word. There is a better way to do this though, which makes more sense considering the second part of this question.</p>

<p>Instead of using a vector, you could use a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trie">Trie</a> which in this case would look something like:</p>

<p>(showing the words &lsquo;sailor&rsquo;, &lsquo;soldier&rsquo; and &lsquo;solder&rsquo;)</p>

<p>{% img center <a href="http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5534/12005243014_69145160ae_o_d.jpg">http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5534/12005243014_69145160ae_o_d.jpg</a> 400 %}</p>

<p>This is a sort of naive implementation, you could compress this by storing strings and only expanding out to character chains if needed, but I skipped that optimization here.</p>

<p>{% gist 8422418 %}</p>

<p>There is a harder version of this problem:</p>

<p>```</p>

<h2>Challenge++</h2>

<p>If you want an extra challenge, accomplish the same challenge but without
knowing the number of times a digit is pressed. For example &ldquo;7653&rdquo; could mean
sold, or poke, or even solenoid! You must do this efficiently with regards to
Big-O complexity.
```</p>

<p>This would have been more inefficient with a vector of strings (you would sort the vector and then for each prefix, print out all subsequent ones until you encounter a string with a different prefix. So it&rsquo;s O(n log n) where n is the size of the dictionary).</p>

<p>With our trie, we can (once we have a list of all combinatorially possible prefixes) look them up <em>quickly</em> (O(k + n), where k is the length of the prefix; O(k) time for each lookup and O(n) time for creating the trie (or O(mn) where m is the length of the largest word, though I would consider that a constant here)).</p>

<p>(Note: there&rsquo;s some duplication of common code, especially in the <code>Trie</code> class; sorry about that!)</p>

<p>{% gist 8460783 %}</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Programming Fun: Circle Area]]></title>
    <link href="http://agam.github.io/blog/2014/01/08/programming-fun-circle-area/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-08T20:22:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://agam.github.io/blog/2014/01/08/programming-fun-circle-area</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Straightforward <em>math-only, no-algorithm</em> <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/dailyprogrammer/comments/1s6484/120513_challenge_138_intermediate_overlapping/">problem</a></p>

<p>```</p>

<h2>Input Description</h2>

<p>On standard input you will be given four floating-point space-delimited values:
x y u w. x and y are the first circle&rsquo;s position in Cartesian coordinates. The
second pair u and w are the second circle&rsquo;s position.</p>

<p>Note that the given circles may not actually intersect. If this is the case,
return the sum of both circles (which will always be Pi x 2 since our circles
are unit-circles).</p>

<h2>Output Description</h2>

<p>Print the summed volume of the two circles, up to an accuracy of 4 digits after the decimal place.
```</p>

<p>This is just trigonometry, so I made some Post-It illustrations. This one shows the general problem we have to solve.</p>

<p>{% img center /images/programming-fun/circle-area-1.jpg 300 %}</p>

<p>Given the centres of the two circles, and their radii, we know <em>d</em>, the distance between their centres and whether it leads to overlap at all.</p>

<p>{% img center /images/programming-fun/circle-area-2.jpg 300 %}</p>

<p>Overlap only occurs when <em>d &lt; 2r</em>. When <em>d > 2r</em> the answer is just the sum of the areas.</p>

<p>{% img center /images/programming-fun/circle-area-3.jpg 300 %}</p>

<p>From this figure, it should be clear that the overlapping area is the segment of the circle subtended by the chord that is common to both circles. We can find the length of this chord by considering the right triangle formed by half of it, the radius, and half the centre distance.</p>

<p>This then leads to the relationship between the area of the sector (<em>A</em>), the area of the triangle inside it (<em>A_1</em>) and the segment area (<em>A_2</em>)</p>

<p>{% img center /images/programming-fun/circle-area-4.jpg 300 %}</p>

<p>Finally, we subtract the segment area from the area of the circle (and then double it, for two circles) to get our answer.</p>

<p>{% img center /images/programming-fun/circle-area-5.jpg 300 %}</p>

<p>{% gist 8323896 %}</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Programming Fun: Braille]]></title>
    <link href="http://agam.github.io/blog/2014/01/07/programming-fun-braille/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-07T23:31:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://agam.github.io/blog/2014/01/07/programming-fun-braille</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here&rsquo;s a simple <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/dailyprogrammer/comments/1s061q/120313_challenge_143_easy_braille/">one</a>.</p>

<p>```</p>

<h2>Input Description</h2>

<p>Input will consistent of an array of 2x6 space-delimited Braille characters.
This array is always on the same line, so regardless of how long the text is, it
will always be on 3-rows of text. A lowered bump is a dot character &lsquo;.&rsquo;, while a
raised bump is an upper-case &lsquo;O&rsquo; character.</p>

<h2>Output Description</h2>

<p>Print the transcribed Braille.
```</p>

<p>{% gist 8308823 %}</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Programming Fun: Banquet Planning]]></title>
    <link href="http://agam.github.io/blog/2014/01/07/programming-fun-banquet-planning/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-07T02:27:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://agam.github.io/blog/2014/01/07/programming-fun-banquet-planning</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here&rsquo;s <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/dailyprogrammer/comments/1rnrs2/112813_challenge_137_intermediate_hard_banquet/">another</a> daily programming problem:</p>

<p>```</p>

<h2>Input Description</h2>

<p>On standard console input, you will be given two space-delimited integers, N and M. N is the number of food items, while M is the number of food-relationships. Food-items are unique single-word lower-case names with optional underscores (the &lsquo;<em>&rsquo; character), while food-relationships are two food items that are space delimited. All food-items will be listed first on their own lines, then all food-relationships will be listed on their own lines afterwards. A food-relationship is where the first item must be served before the second item.
Note that in the food-relationships list, some food-item names can use the wildcard-character &lsquo;<em>&rsquo;. You must support this by expanding the rule to fulfill any combination of strings that fit the wildcard. For example, using the items from Sample Input 2, the rule &ldquo;turkey</em> *</em>pie&rdquo; expands to the following four rules:
turkey almond_pie
turkey_stuffing almond_pie
turkey pecan_pie
turkey_stuffing pecan_pie
A helpful way to think about the wildcard expansion is to use the phrase &ldquo;any item A must be before any item B&rdquo;. An example would be the food-relationship &ldquo;*pie coffee&rdquo;, which can be read as &ldquo;any pie must be before coffee&rdquo;.
Some orderings may be ambiguous: you might have two desserts before coffee, but the ordering of desserts may not be explicit. In such a case, group the items together.</p>

<h2>Output Description</h2>

<p>Print the correct order of food-items with a preceding index, starting from 1. If there are ambiguous ordering for items, list them together on the same line as a comma-delimited array of food-items. Any items that do not have a relationship must be printed with a warning or error message.</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>The second sample input (to take an example) is as follows:</p>

<p><code>
8 5
turkey
pecan_pie
salad
crab_cakes
almond_pie
rice
coffee
turkey_stuffing
turkey_stuffing turkey
turkey* *_pie
*pie coffee
salad turkey*
crab_cakes salad
</code></p>

<p>So this implies a graph that looks something like this:</p>

<p>{% img center /images/programming-fun/graph-dependency-1.jpg 300 %}</p>

<p>Or, if you wish, with the arrows reversed, like this:</p>

<p>{% img center /images/programming-fun/graph-dependency-2.jpg 300 %}</p>

<p>So it&rsquo;s possible to start from the first <code>root</code> node, labelling it as <code>0</code> and its neighbors as <code>1</code>. This process can be repeated, with its neighbors' neighbors being labelled as <code>2</code>, and so on, until there are no nodes left to label.</p>

<p>{% img center /images/programming-fun/graph-dependency-3.jpg 300  %}</p>

<p>Once all nodes are labelled, the solution is just a pairing of these numbers and the corresponding nodes.</p>

<p>{% gist 8293739 %}</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
