<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: clojure | Agam's Mashed-Up Pome]]></title>
  <link href="http://agam.github.io/blog/categories/clojure/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://agam.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-20T02:15:28+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://agam.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Agam]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stuff I'd like to learn in 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://agam.github.io/blog/2015/01/07/stuff-id-like-to-learn-in-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-07T06:49:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://agam.github.io/blog/2015/01/07/stuff-id-like-to-learn-in-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ah yes, the time of New Year&rsquo;s Resolutions. It never ends. Many weeks pass by in a haze of &ldquo;<em>shoulds</em>&rdquo;. So here&rsquo;s something more to add on.</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Keep playing with Go. It&rsquo;s a great, simple language. In particular, I want to try out a whole bunch of crazy experiments.</p></li>
<li><p>Think about the &ldquo;simple text games&rdquo; book. Or bury the idea as soon as possible.</p></li>
</ul>


<p><del>&ndash; Learn a bit more about the JVM (perhaps through Clojure?)</del></p>

<ul>
<li>Stem the atrophy in algorithmic skills</li>
</ul>


<p>&hellip; and there&rsquo;s more I can&rsquo;t remember right now. The first two seem self-evident, so a bit more about the third and fourth. I&rsquo;ve had a deep dislike for all things <em>Microsoft and Java</em> for over ten years now, and I think it&rsquo;s all mostly FUD.</p>

<p>In the case of Microsoft, it was because everything I tried to learn became deprecated as fast as I learnt it, and I quit in disgust (I&rsquo;m told I quit before giving the CLR and C# a fair chance). I was quite naive fifteen years ago and thought that <em>everything</em> that was current <em>then</em> was going to last forever. This extended to such stuff as Frontpage, DDE, COM, RDO &hellip; you get the idea.</p>

<p>For Java it&rsquo;s more vague. I think I never got the <em>hang</em> of it, and then I had a lot of &ldquo;<em>design pattern crap</em>&rdquo; thrown in my face, and my long-last impression was one of incredible, pointless verbosity. Last year though we had someone join our team who had done <em>RealWorkInJava &trade;</em>, and after talking to him it didn&rsquo;t seem all that bad. In particular, the JVM seemed like something worth knowing.</p>

<p>I have pretty much <em>zero</em> experience with hosted languages. One of the reasons for this might be that I always want to know what&rsquo;s &ldquo;really happening underneath&rdquo;, and am deeply suspicious of situations when I <em>cannot</em> know (this is also why I prefer Ocaml/F# over Haskell, but  that&rsquo;s a whole other blog post).</p>

<p><del>Add to this the fact that I&rsquo;ve always been curious about Clojure, to discover all its differences from Common Lisp on my own (there are several rants for and against it online, but there&rsquo;s only one way to find out for sure), and it&rsquo;s a natural outlet for exploration.</del></p>

<p>Which brings me to the fourth point &hellip; I feel I&rsquo;ve seriously forgotten <em>a lot</em> of theory, both in Math and CS, and it&rsquo;s <em>frightening</em>. So I&rsquo;m hoping to weave that (<em>somehow</em>) into my Clojure exploration and kill many birds with one stone.</p>

<p>So yeah, we&rsquo;ll find out how this all worked out, same time next year :)</p>

<p><strong>Update (1/13): This is a bunch of crap</strong> I just realized I wrote a <a href="http://agam.github.io/blog/2014/01/05/resolutions/">similar post</a> last year and did <em>nothing</em> about it (well, ok, I <em>did</em> do the <em>r/dailyprogrammer</em> stuff, more or less), so scratch all of the above. I&rsquo;ll leave it up to remind myself of how foolish this is. I&rsquo;m guessing this will reoccur the same time next year :P. Perhaps the best way out is to make <em>no resolutions</em>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
