<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: complexity | Agam's Mashed-Up Pome]]></title>
  <link href="http://agam.github.io/blog/categories/complexity/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://agam.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-07-06T08:02:25+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://agam.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Agam]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[You say incidental, I say accidental ...]]></title>
    <link href="http://agam.github.io/blog/2015/05/17/you-say-incidental/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-17T03:02:15+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://agam.github.io/blog/2015/05/17/you-say-incidental</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Completely out of context, but it makes a point. Well, <em>some</em> point.</p>

<blockquote><p>Immutant is an integrated suite of Clojure libraries backed by Undertow for web, HornetQ for messaging, Infinispan for caching, Quartz for scheduling, and Narayana for transactions. Applications built with Immutant can optionally be deployed to a WildFly cluster for enhanced features. Its fundamental goal is to reduce the inherent incidental complexity in real world applications.</p></blockquote>

<p>Now, to be fair, it&rsquo;s taken out of <a href="http://immutant.org/news/2015/04/17/announcing-2-final/#What_is_Immutant?">the announcement of a good piece of open-source software</a>, but it&rsquo;s hard to read that last line and not feel like it&rsquo;s the punch line of a bad joke. My reaction is summed up by the first (Disqus) comment: <em>&ldquo;Congrats! I can&rsquo;t wait to find something to do with this. ;)&rdquo;</em>.</p>

<p>You can imagine a sort of automatic generator, that can spit out stuff like this:</p>

<blockquote><p>FooMeister is an integrated suite of HipsterLang libraries backed by SuperBar for web, WooHoo for messaging, YellowDamn for cachine, RedFever for scheduling, and OrangeMayhem for transactions. Applications build with FooMeister can optionally be deployed to a Brouhaha cluster for enhanced features. Its fundamental goal is to reduce the inherent incidental complexity in real world applications.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
