<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Wishlist | Agam's Mashed-Up Pome]]></title>
  <link href="http://agam.github.io/blog/categories/wishlist/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://agam.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-01T16:36:46-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://agam.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Agam]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wishlist [being a brain dump of random things I'd like to play around with]]]></title>
    <link href="http://agam.github.io/blog/2013/10/01/wishlist-2013/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://agam.github.io/blog/2013/10/01/wishlist-2013</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Get acquainted with <a href="http://processing.org/">Processing</a> &mdash; it&rsquo;s quite low performance, but really quick to use.</li>
<li>Write a book (perhaps during <a href="http://nanowrimo.org/">NaNoWriMo</a> ?</li>
<li>Try my hand at an Android app again. The last time I tried, it got to a point where I had to refactor a bunch of Java classes. I don&rsquo;t like Java. I hear it&rsquo;s possible to build some stuff (mostly games) <a href="https://developer.nvidia.com/tegra-android-development-pack">entirely in C++</a> with some &lsquo;shim&rsquo; work to play nice with the rest of Android. So. Worth trying out.</li>
<li><del>Stop procrastinating on doing anything with AppEngine. Just move off AppEngine. Similar to the above, I&rsquo;m not a big fan of either Java or Python. Now that <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products/compute-engine">Google Compute Engine</a> and Google Developer Storage and a bunch of other similar stuff is available, I can be free of the Python/Java restrictions of AppEngine.</del> Do something (maybe host a wordpress blog ?) on the new <a href="https://developers.google.com/appengine/docs/php/">PHP runtime</a> in Google App Engine</li>
<li>Make a toy language. Sure, it&rsquo;ll be dumb and slow as %$#^ but it should be fun to do. <em>Update</em>: How about an implementation of <a href="http://web.cs.wpi.edu/~jshutt/kernel.html">Kernel Lisp</a> ?</li>
<li><del>Make a static blog generator and self-host. Admit it. I&rsquo;m just using Hakyll because it&rsquo;s cool. OTOH the same reason would apply to its replacement, so this is not really a well-formed wish at all</del> Move to a different (read <em>better</em>) static blog generator</li>
<li><del>Find some applications for all the <a href="http://svonava.com/post/62186512058/datasets-released-by-google">Google data</a> that keeps getting publicly released. Most of it is interesting as $#%^.</del></li>
<li>Try my hand at <a href="http://www.topcoder.com/">TopCoder</a> (!)</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
