<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: lecture, | Agam's Mashed-Up Pome]]></title>
  <link href="http://agam.github.io/blog/categories/lecture/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://agam.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-31T07:42:02+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://agam.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Agam]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Minsky Turing Lecture: Part 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://agam.github.io/blog/2014/02/01/minsky-turing-lecture-part-2/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-01T08:55:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://agam.github.io/blog/2014/02/01/minsky-turing-lecture-part-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(This picks up where <a href="http://agam.github.io/blog/2014/01/26/minsky-turing-lecture-part-1/">Part 1</a> left off)</p>

<p>If you thought Minsky cared a lot about how programming languages work, he cares even more about how education &ldquo;works&rdquo;. I recently picked up <a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Society-Mind-Marvin-Minsky/dp/0671657135">The Society of the Mind</a> so it seems a little less surprising, but read on &hellip;</p>

<h2>Computer Science and Educational models</h2>

<blockquote><p>He [the computer scientist] perceives his principal function to provide programs and machines for use in old and new educational schemes. Well and good, but I believe he has a more complex responsibility &mdash; to work out and communicate models of the process of education itself.</p></blockquote>

<p>And lest anyone doubt this &hellip;</p>

<blockquote><p>We cannot digress here to answer skeptics who feel it too simpleminded (if not impious, or obscene) to compare minds with programs. We can refer many such critics to <a href="http://www.loebner.net/Prizef/TuringArticle.html">Turing&rsquo;s paper</a>. For those who feel that the answer cannot lie in any machine, digital or otherwise, one can argue that machines, when they become intelligent, very likely will feel the same way.</p></blockquote>

<p>(If I might digress a bit, there is a very interesting footnote here by Minsky that might completely change the image in your head of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alan_Turing">Turing</a>: &ldquo; <strong>Turing was quite good at debugging hardware</strong>. He would leave the power on, so as not to lose the &lsquo;feel&rsquo; of the thing. Everyone does that today, but it is not the same thing now that the <em>circuits all work on three or five volts</em>.&rdquo;)</p>

<blockquote><p>There is a fundamental pragmatic point in favor of our propositions. The child needs models &hellip;
&hellip;
But to model his own self he <em>cannot</em> use the engine or the organism or the city or the telephone switchboard; <em>nothing will serve at all but the computer with its programs and their bugs</em></p></blockquote>

<h2>Children and Mathematics</h2>

<blockquote><p>Imagine a small child &hellip;
&hellip;
If we extrapolate today&rsquo;s trend, his mathematical education will be conducted by poorly oriented teachers and, partly, <em>by poorly programmed machines</em>; neither will be able to respond to much beyond &ldquo;correct&rdquo; and &ldquo;wrong&rdquo; answers, let alone to make reasonable interpretations of what the child does or says, because neither will contain good models of the children, or good theories of children&rsquo;s intellectual development.</p></blockquote>

<p>He goes on to give examples of how the child&rsquo;s geometric world is <em>so different</em> from ours, such as some numbers having a different <em>weight</em> or <em>depth</em> than others, or not knowing how squares and diamonds are the same shape, as shown below:</p>

<p>{% img center <a href="http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5529/12246677434_860cbfa222_z_d.jpg">http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5529/12246677434_860cbfa222_z_d.jpg</a> %}</p>

<p>This builds up to something I really like (if I may let my personal biases show, I like it because it validates some of my own beliefs): the idea that computational analogies can (and indeed <em>should!</em>) be more generally used to describe patterns of thought and behavior.</p>

<blockquote><p>Before computation, the community of ideas about the nature of thought was too feeble to support an effective theory of learning and development. Neither the finite-state models of the Behaviorists, the hydraulic and economic analogies of the Freudians, nor the rabbit-in-the-hat insights of the Gestaltists supplied enough ingredients to understand so intricate a subject. It needs <em>a substrate of already debugged theories and solutions</em> of related but simpler problems. Now we have a flood of such ideas, <em>well defined and implemented</em>, for <strong>thinking about thinking</strong>; only a fraction are represented in traditional psychology:</p></blockquote>

<p>Some of the ideas listed are</p>

<ul>
<li>microprogram</li>
<li>interrupt</li>
<li>garbage collection</li>
<li>macro</li>
<li>symbol table</li>
</ul>


<p>He goes on:</p>

<blockquote><p>All these serve today as tools of a curious and intricate craft, <strong>programming</strong>. But just as astronomy succeeded astrology, following Kepler&rsquo;s regularities, the discovery of <em>principles in empirical explorations of intellectual process in machines</em> should lead to a science.</p></blockquote>

<p>This finally brings him to a polemic against the nature of math education itself.</p>

<h2>Against the &ldquo;New Mathematics&rdquo; curriculum</h2>

<p>What Minsky seems to be railing here is the excessive formalism in Mathematics introduced early on, where abstract concepts like sets are introduced before trying to create a <em>familiarity</em> with numbers.</p>

<blockquote><p>Because of the formalistic approach the teacher will not be able to help the child very much with problems of formulation. For she will feel insecure herself as she drills him on such matters as the <em>difference between the empty set and nothing</em>, or the distinction between the &ldquo;numeral&rdquo; 3+5 and the numeral 8 which is the &ldquo;common name&rdquo; of the number eight, hoping he will not ask what is the common name of the fraction 8/1, which is probably different from the rational 8/1 and different from the quotient 8/1 &hellip;</p></blockquote>

<p>Here, the fractions, quotients and rationals obviously <em>should</em> be identified with each other, rather than siloed and separated by this &ldquo;maze of formalism&rdquo;. Also &hellip;</p>

<blockquote><p>It is very bad to insist that the child keep his knowledge in a simple ordered hierarchy. In order to retrieve what he needs, he must have a multiply connected network, so that he can try several ways to do each thing &hellip; Emphasis on the &ldquo;formal proof&rdquo; is destructive at this stage, because the <strong>knowledge needed for finding proofs, and for understanding them, is far more complex (and less useful) than the knowledge mentioned <em>in</em> proofs.</strong></p></blockquote>

<p>Minsky suggests that this might stem from a misconception of the form &ldquo;You can teach a child anything, if you just get the definitions precise enough&rdquo;.</p>

<p>He doesn&rsquo;t care too much about overly focusing on set theory either:</p>

<blockquote><p>Set theory is not, as the logicians and publishers would have it, <em>the</em> only and true foundation of mathematics; it is a viewpoint that is pretty good for investigating the transfinite, <em>but undistinguished for comprehending the real numbers, and quite substandard for learning about arithmetic, algebra, and geometry</em>.</p></blockquote>

<p>If there is a way to sum up his argument with one line, it is probably this:</p>

<blockquote><p>The child is expected to learn how to solve problems but we do not teach him what we know, either about the subject, or about problem-solving.</p></blockquote>

<h2>Contradiction and Solution</h2>

<blockquote><p>There is a real conflict between the logician&rsquo;s goal and the educator&rsquo;s. The logical wants to minimize the variety of ideas, and doesn&rsquo;t mind a long, thin path. The educator (rightly) wants to make the paths short and doesn&rsquo;t mind &mdash; in fact, prefers &mdash; connection to many other ideas. <em>And he cares almost not at all about the directions of the links.</em></p></blockquote>

<p>So where does the computer scientist come in to this ? In a heroic way !</p>

<blockquote><p>The computer scientist thus has a responsibility to education. Not as he thinks, <em>because he will have to program the teaching machines</em>. Certainly not because he is a skilled user of &ldquo;finite mathematics&rdquo;. <em>He knows how to debug programs</em>; he must tell the educators how to help the children to debug their own problem-solving processes. <em>He knows how procedures depend on their data structures</em>; he can tell educators how to prepare children for new ideas.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Minsky Turing Lecture: Part 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://agam.github.io/blog/2014/01/26/minsky-turing-lecture-part-1/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-26T00:10:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://agam.github.io/blog/2014/01/26/minsky-turing-lecture-part-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I came across a reference to Marvin Minsky&rsquo;s 1970 Turing Award Lecture. I&rsquo;ve barely read any of these lectures, always assuming they would be empty or pedantic or plain boring. Reading this changed that perception completely.</p>

<h2>Science and Education</h2>

<p>The structure of this lecture seems very interesting to me; it seems to be divided into two parts. The first focussing more on computer science and its failings, and the second on (what seems to me) education.</p>

<p>This post is about the first part. And by &ldquo;about&rdquo; I mean just extracts with minimal commentary.</p>

<h2>The trouble with Computer Science &hellip;</h2>

<blockquote><p>The trouble with computer science today is an obsessive concern with form instead of content.</p></blockquote>

<p>(yes, that&rsquo;s the opening line!)</p>

<blockquote><p>This essay has three parts, suggesting form-content confusion in <em>theory of computation</em>, in <em>programming languages</em>, and in <em>education</em>.</p></blockquote>

<p>(yes, I said two parts earlier &hellip; I just clubbed the first two together)</p>

<blockquote><p>Suppose that we had <em>n</em> computers instead of just one. How much can we speed up what kinds of calculations? For some, we can surely gain a factor of <em>n</em>. But these are rare. For others, we can gain log <em>n</em>, but it is hard to find any or to prove what are their properties. And for most, I think, we can gain hardly anything; this is the case in which there are many highly branched conditionals, so that look-ahead on possible branches will usually be wasted. <strong>We know almost nothing about this; most people think, with surely incorrect optimism, that parallelism is usually a profitable way to speed up most computations.</strong></p></blockquote>

<p>(&ldquo;surely incorrect optimism&rdquo;! I agree!)</p>

<blockquote><p>&hellip; in today&rsquo;s computer science curricula &hellip; almost all their time is devoted to formal classifications of syntactic language types, defeatist unsolvability theories, <strong>folklore about systems programming</strong>, and generally trivial fragments of &ldquo;optimization of logic design&rdquo; &mdash; the latter often in situations where the art of heuristic programming has far outstretched the special-case &ldquo;theories&rdquo; so grimly taught and tested &mdash; and <strong>invocations about programming style almost sure to be outmoded before the student graduates</strong>.</p></blockquote>

<p>(yup, quite true even today)</p>

<h2>The trouble with programming languages &hellip;</h2>

<blockquote><p><em>SYNTAX IS OFTEN UNNECESSARY</em>. <strong>One can survive with much less syntax than is generally realized</strong>. Much of programming syntax is concerned with suppression of parentheses or with emphasis of scope markers. There are alternatives that have been much underused.
&hellip; such devices as infixes and operator precedence &hellip; have their place. But <em>their importance to computer science as a whole has been so exaggerated that it is beginning to corrupt the youth</em>.</p></blockquote>

<p>(I wonder what he would have thought of <em>C++</em> !)</p>

<blockquote><p>The clumsiness, for humans, of writing all the parentheses is evident; <strong>the advantages of not having to learn all the conventions &hellip; is often overlooked</strong>.
It remains to be seen whether a syntax with explicit delimiters is reactionary, or whether it is the wave of the future.</p></blockquote>

<p>(a possible nod to Lisp ?)</p>

<blockquote><p>Much can be done to clarify the structure of expressions in such a &ldquo;syntax-weak&rdquo; language by using indentation and other layout devices that are outside the language proper.</p></blockquote>

<p>(a possible precursory nod to Python ?)</p>

<h2>Moving forward &hellip;</h2>

<blockquote><p>What is a compiler for? The usual answers resemble &ldquo;to translate from one language to another&rdquo; or &ldquo;to take a description of an algorithm and assemble it into a program, filling in many small details.&rdquo; For the future, a more ambitious view is required. Most compilers will be systems that &ldquo;produce an algorithm, given a description of its effect.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>(not sure what to make of this)</p>

<blockquote><p>No matter how a language is described, a computer must use a procedure to interpret it. One should remember that <em>in describing a language the main goal is to explain how to write programs in int and what such programs mean</em>. The main goal <em>isn&rsquo;t</em> to describe the syntax.</p></blockquote>

<p>(Sure, ok)</p>

<blockquote><p>Paradoxically, though modern programming ideas were developed because processes were hard to depict with classical mathematical notations, designers are turning back to an earlier form &mdash; the equation &mdash; in just the kind of situation that <em>needs</em> program.</p></blockquote>

<p>(aha! wait, what?)</p>

<h2>Stay tuned</h2>

<p>So much for Part 1. I&rsquo;ll pick up the rest of the extracts next time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
