<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: blogging | Agam's Mashed-Up Pome]]></title>
  <link href="http://agam.github.io/blog/categories/blogging/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://agam.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-02T23:24:39+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://agam.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Agam]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On moving from development to writing]]></title>
    <link href="http://agam.github.io/blog/2014/07/25/on-moving-from-development-to-writing/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-25T20:11:30+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://agam.github.io/blog/2014/07/25/on-moving-from-development-to-writing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>From <a href="http://mattgemmell.com/confessions-of-an-ex-developer/">Matt Gemmell</a>. I have to say I&rsquo;ve been feeling the same way for some time now!</p>

<blockquote><p>We’ve had our (latest) software Renaissance in the form of the mobile platforms and their App Stores, and I think the software biz is now starting to slide back towards consolidation and mega-corps again. <em>It’s not a particularly great time to be an indie app developer anymore.</em></p>

<p>Small shops are closing. Three-person companies are dropping back to sole proprietorships all over the place. Products are being acquired every week, usually just for their development teams, and then discarded.</p>

<p><strong>The implacable, crushing wheels of industry, slow to move because of their size, have at last arrived on the frontier</strong>. Our frontier, or at least yours now. I’ve relinquished my claim.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Back to Github]]></title>
    <link href="http://agam.github.io/blog/2014/07/25/back-to-github/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-25T20:06:07+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://agam.github.io/blog/2014/07/25/back-to-github</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ok, I&rsquo;ve been talked back off the ledge. Perhaps I over-reacted a bit when I fled to <a href="http://agamposts.tumblr.com/">Tumblr</a> and then to Wordpress.</p>

<p>I will undo some of that and continue living here for a while. Until the next catastrophe, I suppose. Or maybe I won&rsquo;t call it that.</p>

<p>So I&rsquo;ll move a couple of the posts I created there back here and delete that blog.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Living Pseudonymously]]></title>
    <link href="http://agam.github.io/blog/2014/02/19/living-pseudonymously/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-19T01:29:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://agam.github.io/blog/2014/02/19/living-pseudonymously</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For various reasons, this blog is going to be focussed just on C++ programming, as boring as that may sound.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll try not to make it <em>too</em> boring, but we&rsquo;ll see.</p>

<p>Meanwhile everything <em>else</em> will still exist, just not here. Starting with the last two posts.</p>

<p>If you want to try to find me you still can; but I&rsquo;m just not going to advertise it, that&rsquo;s all.</p>

<p><strong>Edit</strong>: Ok, It doesn&rsquo;t <em>entirely</em> have to be limited to that, I can still share some additional stuff, perhaps just not the <em>interesting</em> stuff.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
