<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: chromebook | Agam's Mashed-Up Pome]]></title>
  <link href="http://agam.github.io/blog/categories/chromebook/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://agam.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-30T17:10:33-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://agam.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Agam]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Augmenting my Chromebook with a VM]]></title>
    <link href="http://agam.github.io/blog/2013/12/14/augmenting-my-chromebook-with-a-vm/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-14T17:14:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://agam.github.io/blog/2013/12/14/augmenting-my-chromebook-with-a-vm</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had tried this out about a year ago, creating a small VM instance on Google Compute Engine. But a maintenance window occurred, my VM died, and that was that. I cleaned up and walked away.</p>

<h2>Comparison</h2>

<p>Sometime back, I heard about <a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/">Digital Ocean</a> from a friend. I had just switched to a chromebook and was missing the shell of my previous Linux laptop. So I once again looked into the current cloud offerings.</p>

<p>There is an excellent comparison at <a href="http://cloudpricegrid.com/">cloud price grid</a> so I won&rsquo;t waste time repeating that.</p>

<p>DigitalOcean seems the cheapest for a couple of options</p>

<ul>
<li><em>1core/512Mb/20G &mdash;> $5/mo</em></li>
<li><em>1core/1G/30G  &mdash;> $10/mo</em></li>
</ul>


<p>(See <a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/pricing/">detailed pricing</a>)</p>

<p>However, this is without any firewall or networking capability, and the datacenter seems to be near New York, so that&rsquo;s something to keep in mind.</p>

<p>Meanwhile at Google Compute Engine, the right comparison would be with a combination of</p>

<ul>
<li><em>Persistent disk &mdash;> 20G for $0.8/mo</em></li>
<li><em>f1-micro [1core/600Mb] &mdash;> $0.019/hr</em>
[which by the way at max utilization turns out to be $13.78/mo]</li>
</ul>


<p>(See <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products/compute-engine/#pricing">detailed pricing</a>)</p>

<p>A similar comparison for Amazon (I could be off in apples-to-apples here (what I think are apples may in fact be oranges))</p>

<p><em>t1.micro [1core/630Mb] &mdash;> $0.025/hr</em></p>

<p>So the cheapest Amazon has to offer seems more expensive than the cheapest Google has to offer (both of these instances will be pretty useless for hosting something substantial, but we&rsquo;re assuming the idea here is to have a small &ldquo;developer space&rdquo;).</p>

<p>But keep in mind Amazon also has a <a href="http://aws.amazon.com/free/">free tier</a> so if you just want to try it out for a year, the micro instance is actually FREE (!)</p>

<h2>Getting (re-)started with Google Compute Engine</h2>

<p>I elected to stay with Google. The new <a href="https://cloud.google.com/console#/project">cloud console</a> is much better than it was before, with a nice grouping by project and sub-links to Appengine, CloudSql, CloudStorage, ComputeEngine, etc.</p>

<p>Within the Cloud Engine dashboard, it is possible (and in fact, easy) to create a new VM, set up its associated disk and static IPs, OS, etc from the UI.</p>

<h2>SSHing</h2>

<p>One thing to point out is that the first time I set it up I used the <code>gcutil</code> tool to ssh into the instance; this creates local ssh keys and uploads the public key to the instance (it can be viewed in the <code>Metadata</code> part of the console). So I had to do this from a non-chromebook &ldquo;real&rdquo; computer (though there may be a workaround I&rsquo;m unaware of).</p>

<p>For subsequent SSHs, the recommended way is to use a long SSH command</p>

<p><code>sh
ssh -o UserKnownHostsFile=/dev/null -o CheckHostIP=no -o  StrictHostKeyChecking=no \
 -i &lt;key-file&gt; -o LogLevel=QUIET -A  -p 22 &lt;username&gt;@&lt;ipaddress&gt;
</code></p>

<p>and this worked when I tried it from the computer I signed up on.</p>

<p>Before trying to SSH from a chromebook, you have to copy ssh keys locally (how? I Dropbox&rsquo;d them and then deleted them from Dropbox, which is admittedly less secure &hellip; maybe I should have written it down and recreated manually?!).</p>

<p>Anyway, so once you have copied the keys, you can use the <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/secure-shell/pnhechapfaindjhompbnflcldabbghjo?hl=en">Secure Shell</a> app.</p>

<p>You have to click on <code>import...</code> to select the public/private key pair. At this point, when I used the long SSH command mentioned above, it didn&rsquo;t work. Eventually it only worked when I tried with a blank command (so the only arguments were username, host IP and the key file).</p>

<h2>Chromebook + VM</h2>

<p>Having tried this out for a while, I can&rsquo;t imagine living without it. Obviously it depends on internet access, but that&rsquo;s a common caveat these days.</p>

<p>But I strongly encourage it, since it&rsquo;s a perfect complement to the otherwise &ldquo;browser-only&rdquo; world.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
