<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: screen | Agam's Mashed-Up Pome]]></title>
  <link href="http://agam.github.io/blog/categories/screen/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://agam.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-12-27T03:43:52+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://agam.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Agam]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Setting up Screen]]></title>
    <link href="http://agam.github.io/blog/2013/12/16/setting-up-screen/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-16T05:30:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://agam.github.io/blog/2013/12/16/setting-up-screen</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is pretty much the first thing I do. I&rsquo;ve learned the hard way that I really really need persistent terminal state.</p>

<p>One of the changes I always make is to switch the default key combination away from <code>C-a</code>. Initially I did this during my &ldquo;year of trying Emacs&rdquo; (since it&rsquo;s the default &ldquo;move to beginning of line&rdquo; shortcut). I chose <code>C-z</code> (via <code>escape ^Zz</code>) but you might want to do this anyway if for example you feel <code>C-b</code> would be easier to type.</p>

<p>The other must-have is labels for the tabs. I want to know what I&rsquo;m switching between (a suitable modification to <code>hardstatus</code>).</p>

<p>The status line looks something like this.</p>

<p><img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/BblUW36CQAAG_Ol.png:large" alt="screen status with 3 tabs open" /></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s pretty minimal; you can add an arbitrary amount of customization to your status line, but this is all that I need.</p>

<p>Finally, there are a couple of &ldquo;features&rdquo; that <em>have</em> to be disabled: the screen flash on tab completion (<code>vbell off</code>), and the annoying startup message (<code>startup_message off</code>).</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m sure you know all about switching tabs, detaching and resuming sessions and all that. The only (in hindsight obvious) rule of thumb I&rsquo;ve learnt is to <em>always</em> launch a session with a name. Because you might just want to start two sessions. And then when it comes time to resume them, you won&rsquo;t know which is which. So make <code>screen -S &lt;sessionname&gt;</code> your friend.</p>

<p>Anyway I have a github repo for my &ldquo;dotfiles&rdquo; and you can see my basic screenrc <a href="https://github.com/agam/dotfiles/blob/master/.screenrc">here</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
