<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: linux | Agam's Mashed-Up Pome]]></title>
  <link href="http://agam.github.io/blog/categories/linux/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://agam.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-04-23T06:23:01+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://agam.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Agam]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting into programming, for _real_ and for _free_]]></title>
    <link href="http://agam.github.io/blog/2015/01/02/getting-into-programming/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-02T23:17:08+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://agam.github.io/blog/2015/01/02/getting-into-programming</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I saw an ad for Codecademy<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> in the footer of some web page, and immediately had mixed reactions. I&rsquo;m all for making programming a basic skill alongside reading and writing, but the focus of these &ldquo;bootcamps&rdquo;<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> seems to be <em>vocational web development</em><sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" rel="footnote">3</a></sup>.</p>

<p>This is <del>fine</del>great for people who really want to do that and until now lacked a way to acquire these skills in a focussed manner. But I&rsquo;m worried that this will replace what <em>computer science</em> or <em>programming</em> mean to a whole generation of kids<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" rel="footnote">4</a></sup>.</p>

<p>(Note: to be fair, there are bootcamps which are exceptions to the rule<sup id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5" rel="footnote">5</a></sup>, that focus on a wider array of skills)</p>

<p>While tweaking web pages might offer an instant gratification that can be sufficient for most people, I hope there are lots of kids who&rsquo;d like a bit more &ldquo;hard core&rdquo; approach. In the past, I have always believed this path to best consist of <em>C</em> followed by <em>Python</em> followed by <em>Scheme</em>.</p>

<p>This is still a great way to proceed, but I now think I have a better prescription: replace <em>Scheme</em> with one of <em>Racket</em><sup id="fnref:6"><a href="#fn:6" rel="footnote">6</a></sup>/<em>Common Lisp</em>/<em>Clojure</em>/<em>Haskell</em><sup id="fnref:7"><a href="#fn:7" rel="footnote">7</a></sup>, and replace <em>C</em> and <em>Python</em> by a single language: <em>Go</em>.</p>

<p>The more I think about it, the more I am convinced that Go is an <em>excellent</em> way to learn programming. It fulfills the requirement of &ldquo;learning about the machine&rdquo; (since it&rsquo;s syntactically similar to C, but <em>safer</em>) and being quick to develop and iterate (as in Python, it&rsquo;s very easy to install external libraries, build, run, fix, run again, etc)</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m thinking here of a 10-year old kid (ok, a 10-year old kid <em>who wants to learn</em>). There&rsquo;s stuff like Scratch<sup id="fnref:8"><a href="#fn:8" rel="footnote">8</a></sup> and Logo<sup id="fnref:9"><a href="#fn:9" rel="footnote">9</a></sup> for younger kids, and various programming tutorials aimed at slightly older kids, but what&rsquo;s the best way to target this kid? <strong>I think it&rsquo;s by getting him/her to play around with (1) some flavor of unix, and (2) learn Go. Both are free.<sup id="fnref:10"><a href="#fn:10" rel="footnote">10</a></sup></strong></p>

<p>There&rsquo;s never been a better time to get acquainted with the nuts and bolts of computers &mdash; you don&rsquo;t even need to get a real one! These days major &ldquo;cloud providers&rdquo;<sup id="fnref:11"><a href="#fn:11" rel="footnote">11</a></sup> have some &ldquo;free usage&rdquo; tier, and an easy way to register for a single VM<sup id="fnref:12"><a href="#fn:12" rel="footnote">12</a></sup>.</p>

<p>The best part about using a VM instead of a &ldquo;real computer&rdquo; is that you don&rsquo;t have to worry about crashing it, or otherwise doing anything irreversible. Reached a dead end? No problem, delete the VM and re-provision it.</p>

<p>Which brings me to the second part, using Go. The Go playground<sup id="fnref:13"><a href="#fn:13" rel="footnote">13</a></sup> makes an initial introduction dead simple, but getting up and running locally is just as straightforward. The syntax is very simple and it&rsquo;s easy to bang out lots of code and immediately see it working. (also, one of things a kid <em>won&rsquo;t</em> have to learn with Go? <em>makefiles</em>!)</p>

<p>A question that remains is &ldquo;what exactly to do with Go?&rdquo;, to which my answer is <em>&ldquo;simple text-based games&rdquo;</em>.</p>

<p>So yeah &hellip; this is the train of thought I&rsquo;ve been carrying about for the past few days. BTW &hellip; it&rsquo;s New Year&rsquo;s Eve, so <strong>happy new year!</strong><sup id="fnref:14"><a href="#fn:14" rel="footnote">14</a></sup></p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p><a href="http://www.codecademy.com/">http://www.codecademy.com/</a><a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>See this <a href="http://www.skilledup.com/articles/the-ultimate-guide-to-coding-bootcamps-the-exhaustive-list/">exhaustive list</a> for a &ldquo;30,000 feet&rdquo; overview)<a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>E.g. &ldquo;Deep Dive Coders&rdquo; features <em>HTML5, CSS3, Github, javaScript, jQuery, Apache, MySQL, php</em>, while &ldquo;Makers Academy&rdquo; features <em>Ruby on Rails, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, Git, Agile and Lean</em> (whatever &ldquo;lean&rdquo; means)<a href="#fnref:3" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p>By which I mean ages 9 to 90 (!!)<a href="#fnref:4" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:5">
<p>E.g. &ldquo;Fullstack Academy&rdquo; &mdash; though I&rsquo;m not sure if the name necessarily means what it does, since &ldquo;Refactor U&rdquo; promises <em>Full-stack JavaScript, Node.JS, HTML/CSS</em><a href="#fnref:5" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:6">
<p>Which I think of as &ldquo;Scheme + useful libraries&rdquo;<a href="#fnref:6" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:7">
<p>A contentious choice indeed; <em>more on this later(!)</em><a href="#fnref:7" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:8">
<p><a href="http://scratch.mit.edu/">http://scratch.mit.edu/</a><a href="#fnref:8" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:9">
<p><a href="http://el.media.mit.edu/logo-foundation/logo/turtle.html">http://el.media.mit.edu/logo-foundation/logo/turtle.html</a><a href="#fnref:9" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:10">
<p>as in speech, and as in beer<a href="#fnref:10" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:11">
<p>hate that term, but I don&rsquo;t know what else to use<a href="#fnref:11" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:12">
<p>and even the smallest droplet on DigitalOcean, which is more than enough for this purpose, has a monthly price that&rsquo;s about the cost of a Venti Frappucino<a href="#fnref:12" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:13">
<p><a href="https://play.golang.org/">https://play.golang.org/</a><a href="#fnref:13" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:14">
<p>Although &mdash; thoughts like these are similar to <em>New Year&rsquo;s resolutions</em>, which means you need to consider the possibility that this entire post was conceived in a spirit of naive optimism.¯<a href="#fnref:14" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Switching to KDE]]></title>
    <link href="http://agam.github.io/blog/2013/08/14/switching-to-kde/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://agam.github.io/blog/2013/08/14/switching-to-kde</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been using <a href="http://xmonad.org/">Xmonad</a> for almost a couple of years, mostly because I wanted a tiling window manager that would maximize screen space and allow fast window and desktop switching on my linux laptop.</p>

<p>Recently, I decided to go back to a full-fledged desktop environment again, and I (randomly (please, no &ldquo;Gnome vs Kde&rdquo; flamewar)) picked KDE. The last time I used it was maybe 8 years ago (!), and I was eager to see what I had been missing.</p>

<p>It seems to have gotten better in the same sense that all linux software has gotten better in the last several years (and the machine I&rsquo;m running it on has gotten much faster too!), but I particularly liked the idea of <a href="http://userbase.kde.org/Plasma#Activities">Activities</a>, being somewhat orthogonal to the idea of multiple desktops, and I found it useful to add &ldquo;work&rdquo;, &ldquo;browsing&rdquo;, &ldquo;writing&rdquo; etc areas.</p>

<h2>Minor tweaks</h2>

<p>I had to change the screen rotation of one of my monitors at my desktop, but this was fairly straightforward: [System Settings] &ndash;> [Display &amp; Monitor] &ndash;> [Size &amp; Orientation]</p>

<p>I also always get rid of the useless Caps Lock: [System Settings] &ndash;> [Input Devices] &ndash;> [Keyboard]</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s one issue which I&rsquo;m not quite sure about &mdash; I encountered a <code>no d-bus daemon running</code> message, which I fixed by <code>export $(dbus-launch)</code>, and I haven&rsquo;t encountered it since, but I haven&rsquo;t read up enough to know if this requires some more setup.</p>

<p>I had an <code>xscreensaver</code> lock alias earlier, and I wanted something similar; I assigned <code>klock</code> to <code>/usr/lib/kde4/libexec/kscreenlocker --forcelock</code></p>

<p>Finally, I need a way to setup easy terminal access. I setup <code>Meta+T</code> to run <code>konsole</code>, <code>Meta+R</code> to run <code>krunner</code> (which brings up a &ldquo;quick run&rdquo; box), and (I love this part) installed <code>yakuake</code> which I mapped to <code>Meta+`</code>.</p>

<h2>Other switches considered: Firefox</h2>

<p>I tried moving to Firefox for a while, but I really found it slower than Google Chrome. OK, I didn&rsquo;t personally benchmark it, but several content-heavy websites seemed to load slower.</p>

<p>Also, I had gotten used to certain workflows in Chrome (such as entering <code>amazon.com</code>, hitting <code>Tab</code> and then typing what I wanted to search within Amazon) which were no longer possible with Firefox, and I didn&rsquo;t want to take the productivity hit.</p>

<p>However, I installed the Android app, and activated Firefox Sync and everything worked pretty well. Honestly, I liked the mobile app better. But this is one of those all or nothing switches, since the &ldquo;tab syncing&rdquo; between desktop/laptop/mobile browsers is indispensable to me.</p>

<p>I will definitely consider this in the future again, especially if Firefox&rsquo;s rendering speed improves w.r.t. Chrome.</p>

<h2>Other switches considered: Emacs</h2>

<p>This is one of those eternal conflicts, as I mentioned in <a href="/blog/2013/08/06/slimv/">a previous post</a>. I keep wanting to switch to Emacs, but Vim always remains atleast an order of magnitude faster for me, for most common tasks, so I just can&rsquo;t do it.</p>

<p>As I see it, nothing which begins with <code>C-u</code> can ever be faster than the equivalent two-character command in Vim (in particular, <code>C-x z</code> is 10 times slower than just <code>.</code>).</p>

<p>Recently, I was discussing this with a few colleagues, and one of the things that was suggested was <code>Viper</code>-mode in Emacs as a halfway compromise.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll look into it, see what keystrokes are supported, and if my regular workflow is unaffected, this too might be a switch I&rsquo;d be willing to make in the future.</p>

<p><em><strong>Update</strong></em>: I have since switched from the linux laptop I was doing this on,
to a Chromebook, making the discussion somewhat moot now. However, I am still
using KDE on a desktop environment and loving it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
